Nabil Spann

nabilspann@gmail.com | Fort Collins, CO

SUMMARY

Experienced React-developer and UI developer with 5+ years of experience, committed to using cutting edge technical skills and up-to-date industry knowledge. I have developed applications displaying content from web-based API's. I have experience using Content Management Systems (CMS) such as Kentico Cloud to display content. I have also made UI components using HTML, CSS and JavaScript which are then integrated into Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) which is another CMS. In the future, I would like to work on back-end technologies such as Nodejs and .Net. I would also like to work on cloud platforms such as Azure and AWS.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II (Front-end)

August 2022 - April 2023

American Express

- Made changes to styling of and dynamic content in React components in Amex's custom framework
- Updated multiple Amex repositories/modules to node16
- Increased performance and reduced bundle-size of multiple repositories/modules by 40%-50%
- Updated multiple React components to comply with accessibility requirements
- Increasing code coverage of the application with Jest to 100%

UI developer

February 2022 – June 2022

Knox Financial

- Developed input masking in React with TypeScript to hide any sensitive information the user enters
- Used Angular with TypeScript for the first time to develop forms for job submissions and handled errors from API responses
- Developed email templates on PostMark which were dynamically sent to users when they scheduled for a meeting on the web app.

UI developer

March 2020 - February 2022

Cognizant

Unum project

- Develop React components in Storybook to develop components in isolation
- Use Jest tests to increase the code coverage to 100% as close as possible.
- Document any complex code using JSDoc
- Integrate the Web-apis calls into the front-end application
- Review code that my co-workers have developed
- Integrated Google Analytics into the application

Kaiser Permanente project

- I have created UI components using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for web pages such as navigation, modal, and video components.
- Those components are then integrated into (Adobe Experience Manager) so that those components can be reused to make a page.
- I have made sure those components are responsive in multiple viewports for desktop, tablet, and mobile.
- LESS was used for CSS preprocessor
- I have upgraded the code coverage for a project from 0% to 87% using Jest to test 12 components.
- I have also created static page using React with React-strap and Bootstrap.

React Developer

September 2017 - March 2020

Baha'i National Center, Evanston, IL

- Utilized Axios to access local server-side APIs to get content, change passwords, change contacts, and login credentials.
- I increased the code coverage to 85% using Jest and Cypress tests
- Displayed content on the application using Kentico Cloud content management system.
- Parsed through JSON Web Tokens to display the user's location on a map.
- I have made a four-step confirmation process form for creating an account.
- Created content searching on the React application using Azure functions with .NET/C#. This was done by indexing the content from Kentico Cloud into Azure.

SKILLS

- Cypress
- Jest
- JavaScript ES6
- React
- Styed Components
- Google Analytics
- Material-UI

- Kentico Cloud
- LESS
- Storybook
- SASS
- AEM (Adobe Experience Manager)
- Angular

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2015-2017

Computer Science, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY

CONNECT WITH ME:

- Linkedin.com/in/nabil-spann-7078b2172/
- https://github.com/nabilspann